# ABDESSAMAD JADID

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

**Information:** Morocco, 24 years old, single **Contact:** (+55988389856) (+212608313882)

(WhatsApp Available)

Email: abdessamadjadid@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdessamad-

jadid-b7501710a/

GitHub: https://github.com/abdessamadjadid

# PERSONAL PROFILE

A versatile and self-motivated individual with excellent communication skills and the ability to work under pressure. Extensive experience in IT and manufacturing industries as well. Committed to imposing high quality and works on a team with a strong sense of responsibility. possess a get-it-done attitude while not compromising on quality which generates maximum impact. A very quick learner and self-starter.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Company: Midas Solutions (March, 2019 - Present)

Location: Brazil, São Paulo, Ribeirão Preto

Function: Full Stack Developer

Details: Worked directly in development of a management, validation and storage software of invoices to

comply with Brazilian laws.

### Main activities:

- Work with C # programming languages.
- Using WEB systems development ASP.NET MVC
- Work with HTML 5, jQuery and Bootstrap
- Working with Relational Database
- Create queries, stored procedures, functions, triggers using SQL.
- Planning and applying strategies that ensure the project's quality under development
- · Assisting identifying defects for problem solving, by meeting internal and external demands
- · receiving training on company processes.

**Technologies and Tools:** NET Framework 4.6, ASP.NET MVC, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Oracle, Git, Visual Studio, PL/SQL, Jira and Bitbucket and SourceTree.

Company: 6Solutions (September, 2017 - October, 2018)

Location: Morocco, Casablanca

Function: Full Stack Developer / Customer Service.

**Details:** Worked directly with customer services for the company products. After a while, promoted to work in the development and maintenance of E-Commerce Sport system with products, sales, inventory management, payment and others via web and desktop.

**Technologies and Tools:** PHP 7, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, MySQL, Jira, Bitbucket and SourceTree.

Achievements:

Understand the Customer needs and combining between Customer needs and coding process.

Developing and maintaining numerous functionalities of the web and desktop application.

Company: Xerus Group (April, 2016 - , July 2016) - internship

**Location**: Morocco, Casablanca **Function**: WordPress Developer.

**Details:** Acted as a WordPress Developer of E-Commerce website, to be used to rent apartments and Houses.

Technologies and Tools: WordPress, MonsterInsights Plugin, GREENGEEK web Hosting.

Achievements:

Worked on the application architecture.

Deploying the Plugin in the Website.

Company: Lydec (April, 2015 - , July 2015) - internship

**Location**: Morocco, Casablanca **Function**: Back End Developer.

**Details:** Acted as C#/.NET developer of the new card maker tool, to be used to create and design cards. **Technologies and Tools:** NET Framework 4.6, Windows Form, MS SQL Server, Visual Studio, and Git.

### **Achievements:**

Worked on the application architecture, and database design. Developed numerous functionalities of the desktop application.

## **EDUCATION**

**EMSI** (Oct 2016 – Oct 2019)

IT and Network Engineering
Option (IT methods applied to business management)

**OFPPT** (Sep 2014 – Sep 2016)

Web Development and Graphic Design

# Baccalaureate in life and earth science

El-Majd High School (Juin -2013)

# **SKILLS**

.NET MVC / .Net Core / C# / Java / Flutter / Dart / HTML / CSS / JavaScript / Angular / PHP / Bootstrap / Git / Relational databases (SQL Server, MySQL and Oracle) / Non-relational (MongoDB) / Software architecture / Design patterns / UML / Clean code / Bash Script / Linux Command Lines / Basic Knowledge in ( AI , Big Data , Cloud Computing (AWS , AZURE), Robotics using Arduino and Raspberry Pi 3, Cyber Security , Networking, Industry 4.0).

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Leadership Development AIESEC (09/2019)
- Big Data Foundations Level 1 IBM (05/2018)
- HADOOP FOUNDATIONS LEVEL 1 IBM (05/2018)
- 98-364:MTA: Database Fundamentals **MICROSOFT** (05/2018)
- Windows® Server Administration Fundamentals MICROSOFT (05/2017)

# **LANGUAGES**

• English: Full Professional Proficiency

• French: Full Professional Proficiency

Arabic : Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Portuguese : Elementary Proficiency

German : Elementary Proficiency

# OTHER QUALIFICATIONS AND FEATURES

- > Create from Scratch an E-Commerce system to sell Sport products via web using payment integration.
- Create from Scratch a Resume as a Website: https://abdessamadjadid.github.io/
- > Software architecture and software modeling like Dependency Injection and Inversion of Control.
- > Backend development with NET Core Web API and MVC.
- > Frontend development with Angular.
- > Mobile development to Android and iOS with Flutter and Dart.
- > Relational databases using SQL Server, MySQL and Oracle.
- Non-relational databases using MongoDB
- Using Linux and windows.